What are you doing on this stage
ما الذي تفعلينهُ على هذه المنصّة
in front of all these people?
أمام كلّ هؤلاء الناس؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Run!
اجرِ!
Run now.
اجرِ الآن.
That's the voice of my anxiety talking.
ذلك الصوت الذي يتحدث هو صوت قلقي.
Even when there's absolutely nothing wrong,
حتى حينما يكون كلّ شيءٍ على ما يرام،
I sometimes get this overwhelming sense of doom,
يغمرني الخوفُ أحيانًا من حدوثِ شيءٍ سيّء،
like danger is lurking just around the corner.
كما لو كانَ الخطرُ يترصّد بي.
You see, a few years ago,
تمّ تشخيصي قبلَ بضعِ سنوات،
I was diagnosed with generalized anxiety
باضطرابِ القلقِ المعمّم
and depression --
ومرضِ الاكتئاب...
two conditions that often go hand in hand.
مرضانِ نفسيّانِ يرافقان بعضهما عادةً.
Now, there was a time I wouldn't have told anybody,
وقد مرَّ وقتٌ لم أكن لِأخبرَ خلالهُ أيّ شخصٍ بذلك،
especially not in front of a big audience.
خصوصًا أمام حشدٍ كبير.
As a black woman,
كامرأةٍ ذات بشرة سوداء،
I've had to develop extraordinary resilience to succeed.
كان يجب علي التحلّي بقوّةٍ استثنائية لأنجح.
And like most people in my community,
وكمعظم الناس فى مجتمعي،
I had the misconception that depression was a sign of weakness,
كان لديَّ اعتقادٌ خاطئٌ بأنَّ الاكتئابَ علامةٌ على الضّعف،
a character flaw.
ضعفٌ في الشخصيّة.
But I wasn't weak;
ولكنّني لم أكن ضعيفة؛
I was a high achiever.
لقد كنت صاحبة إنجازات كبيرة.
I'd earned a Master's degree in Media Studies
فقد حصلت على درجة الماجستير في الإعلام
and had a string of high-profile jobs in the film and television industries.
وتقلدت مجموعة من المناصب رفيعة المستوى في مجال صناعة الأفلام والتلفاز.
I'd even won two Emmy Awards for my hard work.
حتى أنّني فزت بجائزتَي إيمي (Emmy Awards) لعملي الجاد.
Sure, I was totally spent,
بالتأكيد كنتُ مُنهَكة تمامًا،
I lacked interest in things I used to enjoy,
فقدتُ اهتمامي بأشياءَ اعتدت الاستمتاع بها،
barely ate,
بالكاد تناولتُ طعامي،
struggled with insomnia
عانيتُ كثيرًا من الأرق،
and felt isolated and depleted.
وشعرتُ بالعزلة والاستنزاف.
But depressed?
ولكن، مكتئبة؟
No, not me.
حتمًا لا، ليس أنا.
It took weeks before I could admit it,
استغرق الأمر أسابيعًا قبل أن أقتنع،
but the doctor was right:
ولكن الطبيب كان على حق:
I was depressed.
لقد كنت مُصابة بالاكتئاب.
Still, I didn't tell anybody about my diagnosis.
ورغم ذلك لم أخبر أحدًا عن حالتي.
I was too ashamed.
شعرتُ بخجلٍ من ذلك.
I didn't think I had the right to be depressed.
لم أعتقد بأنّه يحقّ لي أنْ أكون مكتئبة.
I had a privileged life
فقد كنت أعيشُ حياةً منعّمة
with a loving family and a successful career.
مع أسرة محبِّة ومسيرة مهنيّة ناجحة.
And when I thought about the unspeakable horrors
وكلّما فكرت في الأهوال التي لا توصف
that my ancestors had been through in this country
التي مرّ بها أسلافي في هذا البلد
so that I could have it better,
لكي أتمكن من العيش بصورة أفضل،
my shame grew even deeper.
كان شعوري بالعار يتنامى أكثر.
I was standing on their shoulders.
كنتُ أقفُ على أكتافهم،
How could I let them down?
فكيفَ لي أن أخذلهم؟
I would hold my head up,
لذا كنتُ أمشي باعتزاز،
put a smile on my face
أضع ابتسامةً زائفةً على وجهي،
and never tell a soul.
وأخفي اكتئابي عن الجميع.
On July 4, 2013,
في يوم 4 يوليو، 2013،
my world came crashing in on me.
تهاوى عالمي فوقي.
That was the day I got a phone call from my mom
كان هذا هو اليوم الذي تلقيت فيه مكالمة من والدتي
telling me that my 22-year-old nephew, Paul, had ended his life,
لتخبرني أنّ ابن أخي بول ذو الـ22 عامًا قد انتحر،
after years of battling depression and anxiety.
بعد سنواتٍ من الصراع ضد الاكتئاب والقلق.
There are no words that can describe the devastation I felt.
لا توجد كلمات يمكنها أن تصف الانهيار الذي شعرت به.
Paul and I were very close,
أنا وبول كنّا مقرّبين جدًا،
but I had no idea he was in so much pain.
لكن لم يكن لدي فكرة أنّه يمر بمثل هذه المعاناة.
Neither one of us had ever talked to the other about our struggles.
ولا أيٌّ منّا تحدث إلى الآخر عن معاناته إطلاقًا.
The shame and stigma kept us both silent.
وصمة العار والخجل أبقيانا صامتين.
Now, my way of dealing with adversity is to face it head on,
والآن، طريقتي في التعامل مع المحن هي مواجهتها وجهًا لوجه،
so I spent the next two years researching depression and anxiety,
لذا قضيت العامين التاليين أبحث عن معلوماتٍ عن الاكتئاب والقلق.
and what I found was mind-blowing.
وما اكتشفته كان مثيرًا ومشوّقًا.
The World Health Organization reports
تُخبرنا منظمة الصحة العالمية
that depression is the leading cause of sickness and disability
أنّ الاكتئاب هو السبب الرئيسي للمرض والعجز في العالم.
While the exact cause of depression isn't clear,
بينما يبقى السبب الرئيسي للاكتئاب غير واضح،
research suggests that most mental disorders develop,
تُشير الأبحاث إلى أنّ سبب حدوث أي اضطراب نفسي،
at least in part,
على الأقل بشكل جزئي،
because of a chemical imbalance in the brain,
يرجع إلى انعدام التوازن الكيميائي في المخ،
and/or an underlying genetic predisposition.
والاستعداد الجيني الخفي.
So you can't just shake it off.
لذا لا يمكنك التخلص منه بسهولة.
For black Americans,
بالنسبة للأمريكيين ذوي البشرة السوداء،
stressors like racism and socioeconomic disparities
الضغوطات مثل العنصرية والفوارق الاجتماعية والاقتصادية،
put them at a 20 percent greater risk of developing a mental disorder,
تجعلهم أكثر عرضة بنسبة 20% للإصابة باضطرابٍ نفسيّ.
yet they seek mental health services
ومع ذلك فهم يسعون للخدمات الصحيّة النفسيّة
at about half the rate of white Americans.
بنصف معدل الأمريكيين ذوي البشرة البيضاء.
One reason is the stigma,
لسبب واحد هو وصمة العار،
with 63 percent of black Americans mistaking depression for a weakness.
63% من الأمريكيين ذوي البشرة السوداء يفهمون الاكتئاب بشكل خاطئ على أنه ضعف.
Sadly, the suicide rate among black children
للأسف، فإنّ معدل انتحار الأطفال ذوي البشرة السوداء
has doubled in the past 20 years.
قد تضاعف خلال العشرين سنة الماضية.
Now, here's the good news:
الآن، ها هي الأخبار الجيدة:
seventy percent of people struggling with depression will improve
70% من الناس الذين يعانون من الاكتئاب سيتحسنون
with therapy, treatment and medication.
بالعلاج والمداواة والدواء.
Armed with this information,
مسلحةً بهذه المعلومة،
I made a decision:
اتخذت قرارًا:
I wasn't going to be silent anymore.
لن أستمرّ في الصمت بعد الآن.
With my family's blessing,
بمباركة أسرتي،
I would share our story
سأقوم بمشاركة قصتنا
in hopes of sparking a national conversation.
علي أمل إثارة حوارٍ قومي.
A friend, Kelly Pierre-Louis, said,
صديقة تدعى كيلي بيير لويس، قالت:
"Being strong is killing us."
"قوّتنا تقتلنا".
She's right.
إنّها محقة.
We have got to retire those tired, old narratives
يجب أن نبتعد عن الروايات القديمة الرّثّة
of the strong black woman
التي تتحدث عن المرأة القوية ذات البشرة السوداء
and the super-masculine black man,
والرجل شديد البأس ذي البشرة السوداء،
who, no matter how many times they get knocked down,
وهؤلاء، لا يهمُّ عدد المرات التي غُلبوا فيها،
just shake it off and soldier on.
فقد تخلصوا منها وتابعوا بإصرار.
Having feelings isn't a sign of weakness.
امتلاك المشاعر ليس علامة ضعف.
Feelings mean we're human.
المشاعر تعني أنّنا بشر.
And when we deny our humanity,
وعندما نُنكر انسانيّتنا،
it leaves us feeling empty inside,
نشعر بفراغٍ داخليّ،
searching for ways to self-medicate in order to fill the void.
باحثين عن طرقٍ للمداواة الذاتيّة لملء الفراغ.
My drug was high achievement.
دوائي كان إنجازًا عظيمًا.
These days, I share my story openly,
هذه الأيام، أشارك قصتي بشكل مُنفتح،
and I ask others to share theirs, too.
وأطلب من الآخرين أن يشاركوا قصصهم أيضًا.
I believe that's what it takes
أعتقد أن كل ما يتطلبه الأمر لمساعدة من يعانون في صمت
to know that they are not alone
أن يعلموا أنهم ليسوا وحدهم،
and to know that with help,
وأن يعلموا أنّه بالمساعدة، يمكنهم الشفاء.
Now, I still have my struggles,
الآن، ما زال لديّ معاناتي الخاصّة،
particularly with the anxiety,
خصوصًا مع القلق،
but I'm able to manage it
لكنّني قادرةٌ على التعامل معها
through daily mediation, yoga and a relatively healthy diet.
من خلال التأمّل، اليوجا ونظامٍ غذائيّ صحيّ نسبيًّا، بشكل يومي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
If I feel like things are starting to spiral,
إذا شعرتُ أنّ الأمور بدأت بالتغيّر،
I make an appointment to see my therapist,
أحددُ موعدًا مع المُعالج الخاص بي،
a dynamic black woman named Dawn Armstrong,
امرأة نشطة ذات بشرة سوداء تُدعى دون أرمسترونج،
who has a great sense of humor
والتي لديها حسٌّ بالغٌ من الدعابة،
and a familiarity that I find comforting.
وإلفةً أجدها مريحة.
I will always regret
سأبقى دائمًا نادمةً
that I couldn't be there for my nephew.
أنّني لم أستطع مساعدة ابن أخي.
But my sincerest hope
لكنَّ خالص أملي،
is that I can inspire others with the lesson that I've learned.
أن أُلهم الآخرين الدرسَ الذي تعلمته.
Life is beautiful.
الحياة جميلة.
Sometimes it's messy,
أحيانًا تكون فوضويّة،
and it's always unpredictable.
ودائمًا لا يمكن التنبّؤ بها،
But it will all be OK
ولكن كل شيء سيكون على ما يرام عندما يكون لديك نظامُ دعمٍ يساعدك خلالها.
I hope that if your burden gets too heavy,
أتمنّى أنّه إذا أصبح حِمْلُك ثقيلًا عليك،
you'll ask for a hand, too.
أن تطلب مساعدة أحد.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)